# MAYANK SAXENA

Bhopal M.P. · +919039869059 saxenamayank19@gmail.com, mayanksaxena19@yahoo.com

Sr .NET Developer having total experience of **9+ Years** who understand the business needs, can translate the functional requirements into a technical design specification, code the solution along with unit testing and documenting the results.

Currently working with technologies like C#, MVC, Angular, Design Patterns, JavaScript, jQuery, Asp.net, SQL Server, Entity Framework, LINQ. Having strong written and verbal communication skills, And the ability to work closely with business analysts, system administrators and architects.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### MAY 2018 - TILL DATE - 2 YEAR 2 MONTHS

#### **SR SOFTWARE ENGINEER,** XEEVA INDIA PVT LTD

MVC, C#, OO development (OOPS, Design Patterns), Angular, jQuery, JavaScript, SQL Server, GIT, JIRA. Responsible for Core Application Development and Planning Application Architecture & Communicating with US Based Client.

# SEPTEMBER 2014 – MAY 2018 – 3 YEARS 8 MONTHS SR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ISC SOFTWARE PVT LTD

MVC, C#, OO development (OOPS, Design Patterns), DevExpress MVC, jQuery, JavaScript, SQL Server, GIT, JIRA. Responsible for Core Application Development and Planning Application Architecture & Communicating with US Based Client. Developed reusable libraries along with Custom Web and JavaScript Controls build from scratch.

#### JULY 2011 - AUGUST 2014 - 3 YEARS 1 MONTH

# ASSISTANT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MPONLINE LTD. (JV B/W MP GOV AND TCS)

ASP.net, C#, OO development (OOPS, Design Patterns), SQL Server, WCF, JavaScript, jQuery. Was responsible for Core Application Development, Planning and Release. Developed custom Content Management System, e-governance portals and Data driven websites.

# SEPTEMBER 2010 – MARCH 2011 –6 MONTHS EXECUTIVE OPERATIONS, AEGIS GLOBAL LTD.

Worked as a Technical Support Executive that logs tickets based on the error codes provided by the client, troubleshooting them and identification of the type of issue (i.e. Software related, infra related, client's hardware related etc.) and transferring them to related departments.

# **TECHNICAL SUMMARY**

- Strong Core .NET and Object-Oriented Programming knowledge, including knowledge of multiple design patterns (MVC, MVVM, SPA)
- Experience with ASP.NET, C#, MVC with Razor
- Experience with HTML/CSS/JavaScript like Bootstrap, AngularJS
- Experience with AJAX
- Experience writing applications using jQuery
- Experience with UI debugging and profiling tools
- Experience with performance tuning web applications
- Experienced in GIT Code Repository

# **EDUCATION**

2010

**B.E. IN INFORMATION & TECHNOLOGY, RGPV UNIVERSITY, BHOPAL M.P.** 

**Obtained 67.72 %** 

2006

HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL, MP BOARD OF SECONDARY EDUCATION, BHOPAL

Obtained 61.10 %

2004

HIGH SCHOOL, MP BOARD OF SECONDARY EDUCATION, BHOPAL

**Obtained 67.00 %** 

# SKILLS

- C#, MVC, ASP.net, SQL Server
- jQuery, JavaScript, UnderscoreJS, HandlebarJS, Angular.
- Client Communication.

- DevExpress MVC Controls
- Object Oriented programming in C#
- Object Oriented (Prototyping) in JavaScript
- GIT, JIRA, Source Tree

# **PROJECTS**

# **PROCUREMENT RESULTS, 8 MEMBERS**

C#, MVC, Angular, Web API, LINQ, Entity Framework, HTML and JavaScript Multi-Tenant procurement system that deals with Requisitions, Invoicing, Contracts, Approvals, Catalogs, Inventory required by an organization. Procurement (Request for Quotes), AMS (Approval Management System) and Supplier Collaborator are its modules

# **SUPPLIER RESULTS, 8 MEMBERS**

C#, MVC, Angular, Web API, LINQ, Entity Framework, HTML and JavaScript
Marketplace access by the supplier to track orders, Updating status, Purchase Order Generation

and Invoicing against the Procurement results across all the active clients.

# **COMMUNITY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM, 8 MEMBERS**

C#.Net, MVC with Razor, LINQ, Entity Framework, SQL Server, DevExpress.

Rewriting of a legacy Multi-Tenant Association Accounting and Property management software system developed in classic asp to MVC 4.

Application is responsible for managing Property Owners, Vendors (that works for the property owners) along with Accounting processes like invoice management, Property owner's wallet, Vendor's Wallet, Bills.

#### **INVOICE MANAGER, 2 MEMBERS**

C#.Net, WPF Application, WCF

Creating a bulk Invoice upload application in WPF MVVM Manner to enhance the existing web based document uploader to save server resources and speed up the process.

# **UNIVERSITY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM, 4 MEMBERS**

C#.Net, ASP.Net, MVC, SQL Server, Crystal Report, jQuery.

Developed CMS that can serve all entities related to the University like Student, Courses, Subjects, Exams etc. Developing a database that can be enough normalized to hold all the information related to a university and can act as Multi-Tenant architecture.

### **CONTRACTOR REGISTRATION SYSTEM, 4 MEMBERS**

C#.Net, ASP.Net, MVC, SQL Server, jQuery.

Developed a paperless registration system in replacement to offline papered registration system for Public Works Department. Govt M.P., That provide transparency to the applicant about the application status and Dashboard to the officials for Tracking / Approving / Rejecting the application based on their documents. All contractor information is then Synced to the Tender Portal of Central Govt by consuming a WCF Service.

# **RECRUITMENT SERVICES, 4 MEMBERS**

C#.Net, ASP.Net, MVC, SQL Server, jQuery.

Developed a Centralized system for Recruitment Services that is Serving multiple clients. Client can make changes to the Application Form as per their requirement. All the form related entities like Number of data fields, Validation and Data Format are stored in database and this information generates the Application form. There is also an Approval mechanism that is required when client make any changes to the application.

### **EMPLOYEE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM, 2 MEMBERS**

C#.Net, ASP.Net, MVC, SQL Server, jQuery.

Created a system to manage Employees, Code deployment logs, Their Leaves, Salary Distribution, Attendance, Timesheets and Appraisal System. Employee can raise request related to Hardware / Software / Social etc. issues on the portal.

# PERSONAL DOSSIER

• Languages: English, Hindi

• Date of Birth: 11<sup>th</sup> November 1988

• Marital Status: Single

• Current Location: Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh

• E-mail: <u>saxenamayank19@gmail.com</u>, <u>mayanksaxena19@yahoo.com</u>

• Mobile: +919039869059